### ORIZIO PIERANGELO

(CodFisc: RZOPNG82A09E333T)

Tel: +39.3487036987 skype: pierangelo.orizio

email: pierangelo1982@gmail.com

github: <a href="https://github.com/pierangelo1982">https://github.com/pierangelo1982</a>

Sex: Male | Date of Birth 09/01/1982 | Nationality: Italian

#### **SUMMARY**

Software, Web and Mobile developer, with more than 10 years of technical experience and a passion for working with the latest technologies.

During the years I've working with several languages and frameworks and I've also get knowledge into System Admnistration area.

I am looking for a technical role in the IT sector as a web and mobile developer / or linux system administrator, where I can continue to build on my professional skills and experience. Interested in a role where I can learn new things and make strong contributions to the organisation's goals.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Developer

## July 2016 - October 2016

As freelancer I developed an e-commerce B2B for leading italian fashion's company. http://shop.bergeitalia.com

### **Source Code:**

• <a href="https://github.com/pierangelo1982/djangocommerce/tree/berge">https://github.com/pierangelo1982/djangocommerce/tree/berge</a>

## Technologies used:

- Python/Django Framework
- JQuery
- Ubuntu
- Apache
- Mysql

## Web Developer

### Jan 2016 - March 2016

As Freelance I developed a portal with live-streaming for an helvetian digital radio broadcaster

## http://radiovolare.com/

# Technologies used:

- AngularJS
- Django (for Backend)
- Debian
- Apache
- MySql

.

Web Developer - contractor

### 2014-2016

### GLOCAL s.r.l.

Developed web portal:

- sebinoexpress.com
- gardaexpress.info
- nostalgia.it
- glocalnow.com

## Technologies used:

- Ruby/Ruby On Rails
- Python/Django
- PHP/CakePHP
- Ubuntu Debian
- Apache Nginx
- MySql
- PostgreSql
- Cloud Foundry

Mobile & Web Developer - contractor

2013 - 2014

www.6local.it

I have developed a APP iOS & Android:

- iOS (https://itunes.apple.com/it/app/6local/id894622114?mt=8)
- Android (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=it.local.seilocal&hl=it)

and internal CRM

## Technologies used:

- Java Android Android Studio
- Objective-C iOS xCode/
- PHP/CakePHP
- JSON
- Ubuntu Debian
- MySql

# Web Developer

# 2007-2013 Studio Grafico Password.srl:

Developed several web sites, e-commerce and web-based app.

# Technologies used:

- Wordpress
- Joomla
- Django Framework
- Ruby On Rails
- MySql
- Apache

## IT-technician

# 2003-2007 - Mediacom di Radici Renato:

IT consulting for small and middle companies in the north italy.

|                              | Description                                   | Last Used | Level    |
|------------------------------|---|-----------|----------|
| Operating System             |   |           |          |
| Unix/Linux                   | Ubuntu/Debian<br>CentOS<br>OpenBSD<br>FreeBSD | current   | advanced |
| Microsoft Windows<br>Server  |   | 2010      | Basic    |
| Microsoft Windows<br>Clients | WinXP<br>Windows 7<br>Windows 8<br>Windows 10 | current   | Good     |
|                              |   |           |          |
| Web Servers                  |   |           |          |
| Apache                       |   | current   | advanced |
| Nginx                        |   | current   | good     |
|                              |   |           |          |
| Virtualization               |   |           |          |
| VMWare                       |   | current   | basic    |

| Amazon EC2       | current | good     |
|------------------|---------|----------|
| CloudFoundry     | current | good     |
| Openstack        | current | good     |
| Docker           | current | good     |
| Database         |         |          |
| Mysql            | current | good     |
| PostgreSql       | current | good     |
| MongoDB          | current | basic    |
| _                |         |          |
| Languages        |         |          |
| Ruby             | current | good     |
| Python           | current | advanced |
| Php              | current | good     |
| Javascript       | current | good     |
| Java             | current | basic    |
| Java/Android SDK | current | good     |
| Objective-C      | current | good     |
| Swift            | current | basic    |
| С                | current | basic    |
| HTML             | current | advanced |
| CSS              | current | advanced |
| LaTex            | current | basic    |
| Framework        |         |          |
| Django           | current | advanced |
| Ruby On Rails    | current | advanced |
| Laravel          | 2015    | good     |

| CakePHP              |       | 2013         | basic |  |
|----------------------|-------|--------------|-------|--|
| JQuery               | luery |              | good  |  |
| AngularJS            |       | current      | basic |  |
|                      |       |              |       |  |
| CMS                  |       |              |       |  |
| Wordpress            |       | current      | good  |  |
| Joomla               |       | 2011         | good  |  |
| Prestashop           |       | 2013-2014    | good  |  |
| Drupal               |       | 2012         | basic |  |
|                      |       |              |       |  |
| IDE                  |       | -            | 3     |  |
| eMacs                | •     | current      | good  |  |
| VI/VIM               |       | 2015 basic   |       |  |
| Android Studio       |       | current good |       |  |
| xCode                |       | current      | good  |  |
| Eclipse              |       | current      | good  |  |
|                      |       | -            | 3     |  |
| Software:            |       | -            | 3     |  |
| Adobe Creative Suite |       | current      | good  |  |
| Microsoft Office     |       | current      | good  |  |
|                      |       |              |       |  |
|                      |       |              |       |  |

# Education:

• High School

# **Communication skills:**

- team spirit
- good customer relationship management

# Organisational / managerial skills:

- ability to analyze problems
- ability to solve problems in complete autonomy
- excellent ability to learn
- sense of organization
- ability to organize and manage work independently
- experience managing projects, gained through freelancing experience

## Minor Work (Portfolio):

# Django:

- <a href="http://stucchiluce.it/">http://stucchiluce.it/</a>
- http://www.sanpietroinlamosa.it/
- http://www.studiosagitair.com/
- http://www.francichef.it/
- <a href="http://tecnolabstand.it/">http://tecnolabstand.it/</a>

### RubyOnRails

- http://perfectacavi.it/
- CRM for a company seals (<a href="https://github.com/pierangelo1982/dpgomma2">https://github.com/pierangelo1982/dpgomma2</a>)
- CRM for tire repairer (https://github.com/pierangelo1982/gommista)
- OpenSource Billing Software (https://github.com/pierangelo1982/ Invoice\_OnRails)
- Survey APP (<a href="https://github.com/pierangelo1982/questionarioyoga">https://github.com/pierangelo1982/questionarioyoga</a>)

#### **LARAVEL**

• <a href="http://www.dpgomma.com">http://www.dpgomma.com</a>

#### **WORDPRESS**

- Health-it (http://www.health-it.it)
- ForumBanca (http://www.forumbanca.com/)
- Suardi spa (<a href="http://www.suardispa.it/">http://www.suardispa.it/</a>)

## **APP IOS (Objective-C)**

FNovi (https://itunes.apple.com/it/app/fnovi/id412144526?mt=8)

#### **APP Android**

- Ostelli in Lombardia (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.orizio.pierangelo.youthhostelslombardy&hl=it)
- Bergamo Free Wi-Fi (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.sviluppo.pierangelo.wifibergamo&hl=it)
- Daytona Carburanti (https://bitbucket.org/pierangelo1982/daytona\_android/src)